IL Cafe we have you covered
when was the last time you were in a
counter or a checkout hues where and
that the way you transact and the way
you sort of behave as a customer or a
consumer of a product has changed in the
last five years Well turns out that I've
taken that stock of myself several times
over so I'm pretty excited about this
conversation on aisle Cafe today welcome
to the show my name is sheedle this is a
podcast that is brought to you by ICICI
Lombard and we're about to understand
customer centricity as a crucial
imperative in the ICICI Lombard world as
the effort is to improve access to these
products and solutions now
customer-centric Innovations have been
at the very heart of what the
organization has done in terms of its a
product offering over the years right
from the early days through to that
period of digitization that we were all
part of to the present day today on oil
Cafe we're going to call on the
heavyweights to help us understand this
a little bit better we've got someone
with over two decades of experience as a
professional and certainly nine years at
ICICI Lombard part of customer support
she is in fact the head of customer
support at icicio Lombard vasundara
ghostly is here to chat us up on the
subject of customer centricity nice to
have you here at vasundhara and welcome
to aisle Cafe how are you thank you
thank you thank you very much very well
and very very excited and happy to be
here to share my thoughts on customer
centricity and what we are doing at ipsa
Lombard I'm just going to ask a lighter
question to start with have you also
evolved as a good customer or do you
also do what I spoke of right up front
on the show dear fear absolutely
absolutely I have a tough time refusing
telemarketing calls for example I have a
tough time refusing survey feedbacks for
example because all of those things have
become an integral part and and I
understand the importance of all of that
from the customer
for the customer support teams for the
organization so that's that's something
that I struggle with and yes times have
changed lives has changed when I started
working we used to everybody would take
calls and anybody would do whatever they
wanted to do with the customer and from
there to you know where we are today uh
through the whole gamut of evolving
systems and processes and we when we
started working there were no crms right
and today you can't even imagine life
without them so it's been a big ship
yeah absolutely a big shift and uh
clearly it's become an art and a science
you know that whole day there's nothing
I can talk about about it anymore
Innovations are born of all this kind of
thinking and data and insight that we
have now what if I may ask you there is
a driving philosophy when we talk about
icsu Lumbar and customer centricity
right uh why is it the central pillar in
the organization's vision and mission
for any organization that wants to take
care of all its shareholders and
especially are their customers customer
centricity is a essential pillar of any
kind of vision and Mission that the
organization has and it goes without
saying and uh by prioritizing customer
sector city any organization can
actually deliver innovative solutions
for customers otherwise you know you can
stay in your cocoon and not even realize
when the world takes over so so to
understand customers needs to understand
their changing behaviors to understand
their changing needs to understand the
landscape around the customer how they
are experiencing other industry is not
only your industry and how that is
changing their expectations from you as
an organization all of that is essential
part of being customer-centric as an
organization and customer centricity is
finally what gets you more customers and
it helps you retain your risk current
customers and get more business from
them and yes I mean to add value to the
customers uh Journey with us is what
actually makes all the difference you
know absolutely and an area like this
where ICS is a key player indeed is
something that really touches that
emotional God in uh in people so
although you know I would imagine
responsibility on our shoulders to get
it right now we just spoke about the
then and now sometimes you know how
things were back then Etc and clearly it
is a well-known fact that customer needs
have changed over the years so how does
ICS Lombard Factor these changes or keep
Pace with the requirements you did
mention that there is a way in which you
collect data and insights Etc you
mentioned those calls for example being
in important pipeline to Insight like
that but I'm sure there's things have
changed a lot since that time and then
how does the company then take all of
this data and then make sure it you know
sort of translates those into actual
products that speak to those needs of
the customer great question thank you
um so one is that yes you look at
products and you know you increasingly
uh send out products out in the market
which are digitally available which are
easy for the customer to purchase an
experience uh besides that what you also
end up doing is that you know a lot of
our customers a lot of the world now
especially after the lockdowns and the
covids have adopted to digital Solutions
very very uh like fish text to bottom
right
um people are on instant messaging
platforms can't imagine life without
them anymore and uh customers that
expect that all the businesses will also
communicate with them the way they
communicate with their families and
friends and these channels have become
channels of conveniences and you can't
stay away from them as businesses as
well so we are also hence doing the same
we're leveraging technology uh we're
building service capabilities and uh
we're introducing lots of solutions for
customer Journeys and improving uh
engagement mechanisms with our customers
where
um our customers understand the natural
language of the customer which is
technically called NLP enablement we
have artificial intelligence or AI based
chat Bots we have voice Bots we have
Solutions on the ivr we have visual ivrs
where you know when the customer is on
call with you value value help the
customer through the links and through
through internet so all of those kind of
solutions we have put out there in the
market our customers are experiencing
them every day we get feedback from them
and we keep evolving them we have an app
which is called I'll take care
we have very innovative solutions and
I'll take care uh something from normal
you know claim launching and claim
statuses Etc what customers can also do
is uh Avail features like you know you
can scan your face and get your vitals
um and you know you know how you're
doing key Health vitals so to speak so
no blood pressure or things like that so
it's it's really fantastic to see
customers uh using all of those and and
then and that's how we are putting all
these kind of solutions out there in the
market for customers to experience and
engage with us yeah yeah and you
mentioned so many different Technologies
in fact that you know face scan voila
feature sounds very exciting to me I
think we spoke about it with Girish
sometime back as well uh and I think the
reference that came up was Samosa for
some reason I remember I'm like oh my
God imagine someone looking at you and
saying you beat me then you'll become
fat or something like that actor so a
fascinating what technology can do and
how it can engage with people but I'm
going to come to the engagement a little
bit later Tech that you're very excited
about uh you know personally vasundara
something that is going to really
revolutionize you mentioned a few of
those of course everyone is talking
about AI generative AI nlpu is part of
that whole uh customer experience
Behavior tracking and so on anything
else that you're very gung-ho about that
is going to have a role to play in
productizing needs of consumers yeah
sure so like I mentioned we have Bots
and voicebots with chatbots we created
something called Ria the full form is
the responsive intelligent assistant but
what Rhea actually is an AI powered
chatbot she has ml nlpe capabilities and
she helps us streamline communication
and enhance customers experience through
DIY Journeys
Etc now Ria we celebrated her first
birthday on on women's day this year oh
so she's already one year more than one
year old so mature girl and she uh is
she's she's like she's a human after
we've designed a human of that video uh
she changes her appearance places the
festivals or Independence Day or things
like that so we're trying to keep her
human and she can be accessed through
our website through WhatsApp through
telegram on our call centers when this
voice Squad that's real and our aim is
to and doing all of this why we're doing
all of this is to establish a kind of
emotional connect with our customers uh
though they know that she's a she's a
bot but they shouldn't feel like you
know oh it's a machine and you know I
really don't feel connected so this
state of the art technology that you're
putting in place for Riya is is um and
it's fairly comfortable in in
understanding natural language in fact
the progress we're making is to get Ria
to start talking in Hindi and uh you
know this there is there are lots of
intent training module intent mining
module for for a better conversational
experience with the customers where Ria
is concerned so all of that is really
taking shape has taken shape over last
one year plus because these are Bots
they learn as they experience as a human
being run so so in a sense
um you know when you chat with you it's
like chatting with a human being so
except that you know one of the one of
the party is about it's an evolving
board but it removes
uh Rihanna is also intended to so Ria
what she does is provide convenient you
know easy to access all the time
available kind of customer support for
customers she's able to take claims when
customers have claim requests she's able
to share you know hospitals and network
garages and she's able to give you claim
statuses she's able to give take
announcement requests and and give you a
lost copies she's able to give you
policy copies she's she's able to do all
of these things also understand you know
your coverage and benefits if you want
to understand renew your policy quickly
uh you know within a few clicks all of
these things so Ria has been actually
quite warmly accepted by our customers
and we're very excited by the
opportunities that we are presents for
future she talks about more than a
lacked customers every every month so
that's very exciting and uh we also take
feedback from customers we keep evolving
we keep analyzing so hopefully she's
going to give becoming more and more
mature and and give great service to our
customers so real is an exciting person
out there sounds sounds like a person
that I want to immediately go and meet
you made her sound so real to my years
vasundhara and Report more power to you
and you also mentioned the ilt care app
and they clearly have been you know
fascinated by the phenomenal success
that that particular intervention has uh
has brought for the organization and I
was just thinking you know apps and
trust those things have become sort of
uh integrated my mother if I just booked
her tickets for something and she the
first question she asked me is shall I
download the Airlines app and I'm like
ma why do you need it you got the email
no no the app is like you know I'll have
the app so I just open it and it will be
dead right so yeah that's really what an
app can actually do it can translate
into pure trust in somebody's head and
this is a 75 year old woman I'm talking
about but in any case you know what are
some of those learnings that the ilt
care app has given you real has given
you that you think are going to be
critical in what you do in the future so
what I'll take care of for example does
is it's able to customize personalize
your experience with the organization
you know otherwise you really don't feel
so connected with a company especially
our kind of business where you come to
us only when you have a problem and we
all pray that you don't need to come to
us but yes you mean people come to us
when they when the vehicle breaks down
or they have to go to hospital and
things like that so so for I'll take
care for app to be there with the
customer when they are in the time of
need it makes a lot of difference to the
customers experience and it is designed
to offer personalized solutions to the
customer and cater to their unique needs
so that makes it very very relevant for
each and every individual out there
empowers customer with you know once
it's a One-Stop solution one window
where you know you can do everything
that you want to do whether it's policy
related or claim related what it also
does which is more proactive than than
like I was saying that you and a
customer generally comes to us when
they're in a situation but what I'll
take care does differently than a normal
Insurance business is to provide cater
to customers Wellness needs you know so
all of those things are very proactive
and those are things if the customers
engages with the app on Wellness needs
that really helps the customer maintain
their medical history have make better
lifestyle choices and and those are
things that I think not only does it
help us engage with customers but that
helps us actually add value to a
customer's life
and become more relevant to the customer
so so by providing such uh you know
tailor-made Solutions we we not only
improve customer satisfaction as
everybody would like to and it helps us
really Drive customer attention we've
had lots of good feedback from our
partners Channel Partners customers also
on on the app
um engaging customer through such Tech
based Solutions you know they help you
be relevant and and stay and be able to
analyze customer behavior and you know
behavioral patterns because you get more
information and data from customers
so that helps us enhance and streamline
systems uh product offerings in the
future and even solution service
offerings like what Ria does depends on
what customer is looking for on I'll
take care in the future it helps us
prioritize uh the solutions that we want
to put out there in the market and helps
be more relevant and Target products
better and and stay uh more in customers
life and keep ourselves relevant to
customers yeah so what I'm hearing
vasundara is that you know uh engaging
with the customer clearly this is these
are those times continuous engagement is
really the key to figuring out what
makes to do and what how to do it better
but what is ICS lumbar doing for example
to reach out and educate these customers
on a regular basis uh you mentioned the
I'll take care app but some of the other
cool interesting inner interventions uh
that you thought were like wow why
didn't we think of this earlier it is a
very famous adage you know it says
so that's something that we keep talking
about internally also like you can put
lots of solutions out there but if you
really don't get to the customer and say
Hey you can do this it doesn't really
help right so so yes uh you're
absolutely correct those that's a very
very relevant question on you know how
we get telling the customer hey you know
you can do all this with us so we've
launched a lot of um campaigns for this
for this kind of education of the
customer and not only of the customer
but our Channel Partners our sales teams
our Branch teams etc etc so we launched
a hashtag
Etc which is empower the customers so
where we're telling our own employees on
how to empower the customer which means
when the customer can do things
themselves they're not dependent on
anyone for or come to a branch or call
out somebody or no they are empowered to
do a lot of things their things are
available on WhatsApp and and I'll take
care and you know at their fingertips
it's literally so then we also launched
a power the partner which is ATP you
know which is uh because we've given a
lot of services out there for partners
as well on their Bots and on their
platforms that they engage with us on to
be able to service customers because a
lot of customers in our industry
approach the agent for their servicing
needs so that those also we pushed out
to the to the partner so the partner can
service the customer directly instead of
trying to say okay I've taken your
request I'll get in touch with the
company and get something done even
that's out you know so Etc was empower
the cust empower the customer ETP was
empower the partner we also launched DIY
campaigns which is tell the customers on
how they can do things themselves we
launched a lot of videos for customers
so for example if you if you come and
say okay I need to claim something and
you start a claim process with us the
first thing you get is a video where we
tell you what to expect in the whole
process because a lot of people start
with the claim but they don't know what
to expect next what's going to happen
you have to give documents are they
going to tell me when are they going to
tell me is it going to be today tomorrow
three days five days 15 days what is it
going to be so the videos you know sets
expectation correctly tells you you know
what claim number to hold on to when to
get in touch with us when can you expect
a payment and things like that so those
kind of education uh things we like I
don't know if you bought but we for
example now in general insurance also
has to do kyc with the customer so we've
launched videos to tell the customer
about the kyc process and how they can
get their kyc done with us and their
interactive videos so you can actually
have clicks available on the videos if
you want to intervene as a customer
somewhere and start some Journey you can
actually do that through the video and
we've had really impressive engagement
rates on the video so almost 52
engagement rates which are Partners who
are working on the video were very very
pleasantly surprised by that kind of
number because because we're trying to
intervene and interject the video at the
right place at the right at the relevant
opportunity instead of just you know
bombarding every customer with it effect
if you don't have a claim with us if I
send you a claim education video you're
not going to really do much about it
just keep it on the side for the future
or maybe not do that as well so we're
trying to interject and intervene at the
right place educate at the right time so
that kind of assistance that we're
giving utilizing all these kind of
facilities and faculties is really
helping in like I said empowering our
customers that's what we actually
believe in you know engage and empower
the customers so that you know there's
absolutely smooth Journey I'm glad that
you brought up that otherwise you know
painful part of that customer experience
which is usually the claims process and
the ways in which you are working around
or through the claims process to even
engage with the customer through that
interesting thing anything else you want
to call out for sundara in terms of the
claims process because I do believe
there are people out there who want to
know okay all this is very well this
you picked out for us
but tell me a little bit more about this
part so you know we're all sort of
breathing a bit more easy
sure the the AI based uh claim
processing and AI based and ml based
clean processing that's quick easy Swift
for the customer so for example a
customer can integrate claim on uh Ria
on WhatsApp when they call up the call
center for example if you call up the
call center for launching a motor claim
you actually talk to Riya and it's a
much smaller process now we've done away
with a lot of Frills uh kept them for
later so it's very easy and quick to
launch a claim with us and then for us
to fulfill that claim for you or to
service you through the claim
um so for example you can actually do
the video of your vehicle and send it to
us and and then we process the claim on
that on the basis of that video AI has
reduced uh cashless Health claim request
approval time so that kind of changes
those kind of benefits for the customers
we've been able to derive from all these
initiatives this kind of fast decision
making on cashless it enables store
treatment to really start quickly and it
reduces the customer's anxiety time the
wait time that they otherwise you know
they're like panicking whether it's
going to happen not happen and so we
produce that emergency situations you
need to be out there for the customer
and do it really quickly the visual ivr
that I was talking about earlier is a
platform that provides a seamless claim
information you know and especially for
motor insurance customers like I was
saying if you call up the call center
Immortal Insurance claim registration is
super smooth much shorter than it used
to be so the processes also we worked on
and made them made them much easier the
the bot guides you at every step uh and
it collects all the information
real-time basis it goes to the claims
team there's no there's no wait time or
there's no you know scheduler that's
running or things like that everything
is happening seamlessly and real time so
voicebot offers solution 24x7 because
it's on our 24x7 call center number
voice what plus our team of call center
folks is always there to help customers
additionally customers can track their
health claim and motor claim statuses
real time that's very helpful for them
like I said Ria helps on on WhatsApp you
can go to website and check they can go
to I'll take care and check Riya takes
care of you know the entire claim
process from start to end though with
those kind of offerings are really
helpful but what does the future look
like if I were to sort of ask you to
train your vision into the next five ten
year window from customer Behavior here
and now
um and the kind of technologies that are
underway what do you expect or what do
you see the road map look like for ICS
in robot the way the world is evolving
and the way the technology is evolving I
don't think anybody can give you a 510
year window into anything at all so it's
very exciting to see chat Deputy happen
we're trying to see how how to leverage
chant GPT for example so those kind of
things are so much you know just one day
something gets launched and it just
changes your your plan for the year so
forget the five year and the 10 year
window I like you repeated and I shared
that it's very exciting times for all of
us you know in any kind of field I think
uh the way technology is disrupting your
plans every day it's really exciting but
we what we want to what we have signed
up for is to continuously work
relentlessly on whatever is the new
technology you know whether it's AI
robotics you know video enabled things
whatever new Solutions if people are
coming up with we sign up for
experimenting that's what we've promised
ourselves and that's what we promised
our customers
um we're going to stay continuously
focused on building uh robust Solutions
and business model that
stands on you know solid fillers of um
one less prudent risk management uh
that's that's the key to our business
then very technology driven in your face
solutions for customers and our Channel
partners and the entire distribution
Network we have a huge team of very very
passionate they own their work
of employees and um I think we have the
trust of the customers
um they are always at the Forefront of
trying new things that we keep launching
which makes it all the more exciting and
and yeah so I think future is just
exciting that's all nobody can give you
a five year tenure window so roadmap is
Clear customer centricities will just
stay in the middle so I'm going to keep
working and experimenting so till the
time we keep doing that I think we're on
a roll you know one thing I'm sure of is
going to happen in the next five ten
years although we can't talk about
anything else there are going to be a
lot more cups in the in the background
over there for you in your in your
office absolutely you're so proud of
them I ensure that out there for
everybody to say our teams are very
excited to always go out and and keep
showcasing what we're doing because
um you know the world is not such that
you you keep your thoughts close and say
okay I'm doing this I don't want to
share it with anybody because you have
to go out there and talk about things
and then you learn three more things
um ultimately your uniqueness stands out
because your uniqueness lies in your
passionate people in in your capability
and capacity to experiment in your risk
taking abilities nobody can copy that at
all so never shy away from sharing and
getting our accolades
fantastic and here's wishing you many
more of those you and the team and thank
you so much vasundhara for making this
quite a such a delightful experience you
know Master storytellers I must say that
because now I will never listen to that
song
it's been a pleasure talking to you and
I hope that this also goes towards
educating all our employees on what what
all they can expect to see and um and
also driving Customer Center City
irrespectively over the function they
are in so thank you so much great
questions hopefully I've been able to
answer them and throw some light on them
and all the best to everybody who's
working on all of these initiatives
thank you
you were listening to Il Cafe we have
you covered
foreign